<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Policy analysis &#8211; Minahil</title>
	<atom:link href="/portfolio-category/policy-analysis/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2016 19:39:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.7.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Gender in Water Programs in Rural Rwanda</title>
		<link>/portfolio-item/gender-in-water-programs-in-rural-rwanda/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2015 04:20:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[theadmin]]></dc:creator>
		
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?post_type=lato_portfolio&#038;p=155</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Client: Global Grassroots [in partnership with The Coca-Cola Africa Foundation] I co-conducted a policy analysis on the exclusion of women and girls from decision-making processes in water projects in rural Rwanda and the related problems of misinformed interventions and misallocated donor resources. My partner and I summarized the precedence for gender mainstreaming and integrated water [...]<p><a class="btn btn-primary-color btn-tiny more-btn" href="/portfolio-item/gender-in-water-programs-in-rural-rwanda/">Read More &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>Client: <a href="http://www.globalgrassroots.org/" target="_blank">Global Grassroots</a> [in partnership with The Coca-Cola Africa Foundation]</h2>
<p>I co-conducted a policy analysis on the exclusion of women and girls from decision-making processes in water projects in rural Rwanda and the related problems of misinformed interventions and misallocated donor resources. My partner and I summarized the precedence for gender mainstreaming and integrated water resource management (both of which advocate women’s pivotal role in water management) and surveyed the landscape of aid donors focusing on water in East Africa. With constant iterations based on our research and feedback from our client, we developed three detailed options focused on coalition-building, evidence-building, and extending the status quo. We evaluated these options against criteria based on our client’s priorities and provided a thorough explanation of the evaluation. Finally we provided our client with a recommendation and a database of resources to galvanize the implementation of the recommendation.</p>
<p>From our client:</p>
<p><i>The research and analysis conducted by Minahil Amin and Jenni Jung was extremely comprehensive and professional in its quality and presentation. They provided invaluable insights and strategies for expanding our impact and influence in the field of women-led water infrastructure development.  Their report has helped us make an effective case for our programs with donors and partners alike, and we are deeply grateful for their work which has added to our knowledge base in important ways. </i></p>
<p><i>-Gretchen Wallace, Founder and President of Global Grassroots   </i></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Improving Literacy in Zambia</title>
		<link>/portfolio-item/improving-literacy-in-zambia/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2015 04:19:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[theadmin]]></dc:creator>
		
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?post_type=lato_portfolio&#038;p=169</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Client: Chemonics International [for USAID and The Zambian Ministry of Education] I worked in a four-person team to identify both the root causes behind the low literacy rate in Zambia and the implementation challenges of an English language teaching policy the Zambian government had recently passed. Our team researched evidence-based best practices for literacy improvement, developed criteria [...]<p><a class="btn btn-primary-color btn-tiny more-btn" href="/portfolio-item/improving-literacy-in-zambia/">Read More &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>Client: <a href="http://www.chemonics.com/Pages/Home.aspx" target="_blank">Chemonics International</a> [for USAID and <a href="http://www.moe.gov.zm/" target="_blank">The Zambian Ministry of Education</a>]</h2>
<p>I worked in a four-person team to identify both the root causes behind the low literacy rate in Zambia and the implementation challenges of an English language teaching policy the Zambian government had recently passed. Our team researched evidence-based best practices for literacy improvement, developed criteria to assess potential solutions (cost-effectiveness, community support, sustainability), and designed four policy alternatives, complete with implementation plans, to improve literacy and overall quality of education in Zambia. After evaluating these alternatives against the criteria and making the trade-offs of each alternative clear, we provided Chemonics with a recommendation.<br />
The analysis involved extensive research – understanding the Zambian context and work in literacy improvement – through expert interviews and literature reviews. Our cost-effectiveness analysis involved calculating the costs of the various components of each policy alternative and comparing those to the projected improvements in literacy.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
