<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Policy memo &#8211; Minahil</title>
	<atom:link href="/portfolio-category/policy-memo/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2016 19:39:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.7.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Mitigating the Push Factors of Early Retirement</title>
		<link>/portfolio-item/mitigating-the-push-factors-of-early-retirement/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2015 04:14:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[theadmin]]></dc:creator>
		
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?post_type=lato_portfolio&#038;p=221</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Citizens&#8217; early exit from the workforce exacerbates the crisis of the United States&#8217; public pension system. A number of push factors, such as age discrimination, stereotypes related to the elderly, and misconceptions about older workers’ productivity, compel older workers to retire before their functional capacity to work significantly decreases. This decision memo proposes policies that [...]<p><a class="btn btn-primary-color btn-tiny more-btn" href="/portfolio-item/mitigating-the-push-factors-of-early-retirement/">Read More &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Citizens&#8217; early exit from the workforce exacerbates the crisis of the United States&#8217; public pension system. A number of push factors, such as age discrimination, stereotypes related to the elderly, and misconceptions about older workers’ productivity, compel older workers to retire before their functional capacity to work significantly decreases. This decision memo proposes policies that can help combat these push factors and assesses the trade-offs between these policies.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Welfare State and Women&#8217;s Economic Autonomy</title>
		<link>/portfolio-item/the-welfare-state-and-womens-economic-autonomy/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2015 04:12:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[theadmin]]></dc:creator>
		
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?post_type=lato_portfolio&#038;p=220</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This decision memo presents the argument that the limits on women’s economic autonomy are propagated by the liberal welfare regime. Women who want to work have the dual obligation of housework, especially childcare, and paid work. The liberal welfare regime neglects the family policies that would allow women a more equal footing with men in [...]<p><a class="btn btn-primary-color btn-tiny more-btn" href="/portfolio-item/the-welfare-state-and-womens-economic-autonomy/">Read More &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This decision memo presents the argument that the limits on women’s economic autonomy are propagated by the liberal welfare regime. Women who want to work have the dual obligation of housework, especially childcare, and paid work. The liberal welfare regime neglects the family policies that would allow women a more equal footing with men in paid work. This decision memo proposes potential options to address this neglect and weighs the trade-offs between these policies. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Narrative on Non-Communicable Diseases</title>
		<link>/portfolio-item/the-narrative-on-non-communicable-diseases/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2015 04:11:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[theadmin]]></dc:creator>
		
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?post_type=lato_portfolio&#038;p=214</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This policy brief examines the narrative in the global health aid community of &#8220;lifestyle choices,” which holds that non-communicable diseases are often the result of a series of individuals’ lifestyle choices.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This policy brief examines the narrative in the global health aid community of &#8220;lifestyle choices,” which holds that non-communicable diseases are often the result of a series of individuals’ lifestyle choices.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Congestion Pricing: London to DC</title>
		<link>/portfolio-item/congestion-pricing-london-to-dc/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2015 04:09:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[theadmin]]></dc:creator>
		
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?post_type=lato_portfolio&#038;p=223</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This policy brief examines London&#8217;s implementation of a congestion pricing scheme to address urban congestion and pollution and the applicability of this scheme to the Washington DC context.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This policy brief examines London&#8217;s implementation of a congestion pricing scheme to address urban congestion and pollution and the applicability of this scheme to the Washington DC context.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Racial Bias in Policing: Interventions</title>
		<link>/portfolio-item/racial-bias-in-policing-interventions/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2015 04:08:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[theadmin]]></dc:creator>
		
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?post_type=lato_portfolio&#038;p=215</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[There is strong evidence of widespread racial discrimination in policing in the United States. Specifically, police disproportionately target and use unreasonable force against African-Americans. This discrimination can be partially attributed to individual police officers’ implicit racial biases. This policy memo presents two major social psychological interventions that can help counteract the biases that lead to [...]<p><a class="btn btn-primary-color btn-tiny more-btn" href="/portfolio-item/racial-bias-in-policing-interventions/">Read More &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There is strong evidence of widespread racial discrimination in policing in the United States. Specifically, police disproportionately target and use unreasonable force against African-Americans. This discrimination can be partially attributed to individual police officers’ implicit racial biases. </p>
<p>This policy memo presents two major social psychological interventions that can help counteract the biases that lead to racial discrimination in policing: (1) developing ethical scripts and related simulations to help officers prepare for situations where implicit bias is salient and (2) changing the default rule for whether police officers should engage perceived threats with violence.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Campus Racial Climate at the University of Virginia</title>
		<link>/portfolio-item/campus-racial-climate-at-the-university-of-virginia/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2015 04:07:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[theadmin]]></dc:creator>
		
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?post_type=lato_portfolio&#038;p=224</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In 2015, events concerning race around the nation triggered a critical introspection on the state of our society. The University of Virginia, too, was compelled to address race relations on its campus and in the larger community. This policy proposal seeks to outline the current research on racial climates in higher education, the implications of [...]<p><a class="btn btn-primary-color btn-tiny more-btn" href="/portfolio-item/campus-racial-climate-at-the-university-of-virginia/">Read More &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In 2015, events concerning race around the nation triggered a critical introspection on the state of our society. The University of Virginia, too, was compelled to address race relations on its campus and in the larger community. This policy proposal seeks to outline the current research on racial climates in higher education, the implications of hostile climates, and potential strategies universities can implement to address hostile climates &#8211; in particular, conducting campus racial climate assessments, increasing intergroup contact, transforming curriculum to reflect more diverse perspectives, and explicitly committing to a multiracial campus climate.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
