<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Data analysis &#8211; Minahil</title>
	<atom:link href="/portfolio-category/data-analysis/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2016 19:39:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.7.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Readiness for the Future Economy: Foreign Residency and Occupation</title>
		<link>/portfolio-item/readiness-for-the-future-economy-foreign-residency-and-occupation/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2015 04:15:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[theadmin]]></dc:creator>
		
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?post_type=lato_portfolio&#038;p=219</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In context of both the discussions of the United States’ readiness for the future economy in terms of its STEM capacity and the debates on immigration reform, this research paper seeks to assess whether there is a relationship between foreign residency and occupation. In particular, it explores the relationship between exposure to foreign factors (defined [...]<p><a class="btn btn-primary-color btn-tiny more-btn" href="/portfolio-item/readiness-for-the-future-economy-foreign-residency-and-occupation/">Read More &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In context of both the discussions of the United States’ readiness for the future economy in terms of its STEM capacity and the debates on immigration reform, this research paper seeks to assess whether there is a relationship between foreign residency and occupation.<br />
In particular, it explores the relationship between exposure to foreign factors (defined as living in a foreign country or having immigrant parents) and occupation choice for the 1997 National Longitudinal Survey cohort. The analysis finds that these foreign factors do relate to individuals’ proclivities to work in certain industries, although these industries aren’t necessarily ones identified as important for future economic preparedness.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dropout Rates in US Public Universities</title>
		<link>/portfolio-item/dropout-rates-in-us-public-universities/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2015 04:13:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[theadmin]]></dc:creator>
		
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?post_type=lato_portfolio&#038;p=218</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This report seeks possible explanations for the differential college dropout rates at one hundred and four public universities across the United States. In particular, it examines the effect of five institutional and financial variables &#8211; percentage of minority students, number of employees, academic support spending, grant aid, and tuition &#8211; on college dropout rates. Statistical [...]<p><a class="btn btn-primary-color btn-tiny more-btn" href="/portfolio-item/dropout-rates-in-us-public-universities/">Read More &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This report seeks possible explanations for the differential college dropout rates at one hundred and four public universities across the United States. In particular, it examines the effect of five institutional and financial variables &#8211; percentage of minority students, number of employees, academic support spending, grant aid, and tuition &#8211; on college dropout rates. Statistical methods included t-tests, correlation, OLS, and regression tests, as well as checks for heteroscedasticity and multicollinearity. The analysis ultimately finds that larger numbers of university employees, higher rates of academic support spending, and greater amounts of grant aid all have statistically significant relationships with lower college dropout rates.    </p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
